# Ivars Melecis

Email Address

ivars.melecis@gmail.com 1 Bradley drive, Grantham Lincolnshire, NG31 7WN

Website https://melecis.co.uk/ Phone

07754527480

# **OBJECTIVE**

Highly self-motivated individual with great attention to detail and over 9 years of experience in web development industry is looking for new challenge. Gained variety of skills over the years including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Photoshop, XD, WordPress.

Looking forwards to expanding and using current skill set to help reaching KPI's while delivering quality code and making the Web a better place.

**SKILLS** 

**ROLE** 

Advanced: HTML, CSS and CSS3, JavaScript, WordPress

Intermediate: MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Adobe Photoshop, jQuery, PHP, GitHub

Entry Level: SCSS, MySQLi, Adobe XD

Worked with: JWT, Winston, Netlify, Heroku, PM2

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Full-stack web developer

Ketchup MarketingBuckminster November 2020 - Present

### Web developer

Ketchup MarketingBuckminster November 2019 - November 2020

# Website build team leader (Junior Front-end developer)

PrimarySite Limited Newark-on-Trent August 2017 - November 2019

# Website builder (Junior Front-end developer)

PrimarySite Limited Newark-on-Trent January 2015 - August 2017

# Freelance web developer

Grantham April 2013 - January 2015

## RESPONSIBILITIES INCLUDED:

- Maintaining bespoke in-house WordPress template
- Developing websites using SCSS, HTML, PHP, Gulp, NPM, Adobe XD
- Creating plugins for in-house needs using vanilla JS
- Building e-commerce sites
- Maintaining existing websites
- Performing technical SEO on request (SEMrush, Web CEO)
- Producing websites using SCSS, HTML, JavaScript, Gulp, Node, WordPress and
- Creating automation tools for in-house needs
- Creating and maintaining documentation.
- Involved in an in-house automation tool creation that saves company 50 minutes every day and ensures testing content consistency Involved in code snippet bank development to streamline build processes
- Leading team of 5 to deliver team and department set KPI's
- Created several easy-to-use JavaScript plugins for the team to push our abilities andenhance functionality of our websites Created and maintained documentation for tools used in our day-to-day job
- PSD to working websites using HTML, CSS, and jQuery
- Contributing to teams brainstorming sessions to satisfy customer needs and innovate build processes
- Slicing Photoshop files for usage on illustration-based designs allowing dynamic content
- Best performer exceeding personal KPI's
- Working with customers to develop various small business and entertainment websites
- Used PHP along with MSQLI to create and maintain gaming community web sitewith custom CMS
- Worked with Adobe Dreamweaver as base for my projects

### **EDUCATION**

# **Arden University**

Manchester October 2020 - Present

# Programming technician

Centre of distance learning and professional continuing education of Latvia December 2017 - December 2019

# **Certificate of Competency**

Home Learning College (UK) 2013

# Secondary School

Karla Videnieka Secondary School No 77 Riga, Latvia 2008 BSC (Hons) Computing, Information Technology

#### Comparison:

UK Framework levels: RQF Level 3/ SCQF Level 6-7/ CQFW Level 3 Comparable UK qualifications: Level 3 NVQ / SVQ Level 3/ SQA Professional Development Award at SCQF Levels 6 (UK NARIC)

#### Course included:

- Network and database technologies Software Engineering
- WEB technologies and WEB programming Project management
- Programming

#### Course included:

- Internet Fundamentals and Site Planning
- Adobe Dreamweaver's Interface
- Design Principles and Graphic Design
- Creating a Complete Web Standards Site and Productivity features Adding/Styling
  pages features and publishing/managing site Advanced web development HTML5,
  CSS3, PHP and MySQL Bitmaps, frame-by-frame animation, interactivity, and
  publishing
- Created custom WordPress theme using Adobe Dreamweaver

### Comparison:

UK Framework levels: RQF Level 3/ SCQF Level 6 / CQFW 3 Comparable UK qualifications: GCE Advanced Subsidiary (AS) level /Scottish Higher Additional comparison information: Every subject passed may be considered at least comparable to GCSE grades A\* - C (UK NARIC)

#### **CERTIFICATES & COURSES**

IELTS language test (Academic) band 7- 2020

Adobe Certified Expert - Dreamweaver CC - 2016

Adobe Certified Associate in Rich Media Using Flash Professional CS6 - 2014

 ${\bf Adobe\ Certified\ Associate\ in\ Web\ Communication\ Using\ Adobe\ Dreamweaver\ CS6-2014}$